# GABRIEL ZURITA WEB DEVELOPER

# **>** CONTACT

gabezurita@gmail.com

www.gabo.online

**\** 315-395-3987

**f** gzurita **y** gabezurita

in gabezurita 🖸 gabezurita

# > SKILLS

#### **LANGUAGES**

Ruby

JavaScript

#### **DATABASES**

PostgreSQL

**SQLite** 

MySQL

JQL

#### **TESTING**

RSpec

Jasmine

Capybara

#### **METHODOLOGIES**

Test Driven Development

Agile Development

Object-Oriented Design

Git Workflow

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

Rails

Sinatra

Bootstrap

AngularJS

#### FRONT-END

HTML

CSS

jQuery

AJAX

## **MEDIA**

Photography

Adobe Suite

# CRM

Salesforce

#### DATA ANALYSIS

Regression Analysis ArcGIS

#### **SPOKEN LANGUAGES**

Native fluency in Spanish and English

# **>** SUMMARY

Hello! I'm Gabriel, a Chilean-American web developer living in Washington, DC and working at Optoro as a Platform Stability Analyst.

# > PROJECTS

#### JIRA REPORTING

Jira Reporting is a Ruby gem that is used to mimic the functionality of Jira Service Desk, saving Optoro some \$3,000 USD per month in user costs. The gem uses the Jira API to update Jira issue custom fields with Service Level Agreement and time tracking data, to send automated notifications, to analyze tech team performance, and create stability and scaling reports for the Director of Platform Stability, the CTO, and the rest of Optoro.

#### GLOBAL HOST

A mobile app that lets users connect with local guides in foreign cities who share common interests and create an itinerary for a day's visit so as to experience that city like a local. Global Host was an eight-day, fourperson final project for Dev Bootcamp. It was built on **Rails**, utilized the **Google Maps JavaScript AP**I, relied on **Materialize** for visual elements, and was consistently tested using **Codeship** continuous integration. Visit the live app at global-host.herokuapp.com and view the project code at github.com/gabezurita/Global-Host

#### PHOTOGRAPHY PORTFOLIO

I took bi-weekly photography lessons for two years in 2010 and have continued the hobby since. It helps me relax and be present as I capture the moment. Take a look at my shots at flickr.com/gabezurita

## > EXPERIENCE

#### Platform Stability Analyst · OPTORO

Nov 2016 to Current, Nov 2016 to Current · Washington, D.C.

Optoro's Platform Stability team is responsible for ensuring that our systems are functioning around the clock and is expected to be available to coordinate response to incidents at any time. We help deliver enterprise-grade stability in all of Optoro's products.

We work with our engineering teams to develop dashboards, alerts, and other tools to effectively monitor and report on information like system uptime, server capacity utilization, system scaling, units shipped, SLA metrics, and other vital business and technical metrics.

#### Web Developer in Training · DEV BOOTCAMP

Feb 2016 to Jul 2016 · Chicago

In Dev Bootcamp, I spent 6 intense, immersive months studying back-end and front-end languages and frameworks. We applied agile and test-driven development practices as we pair programmed projects together throughout the course using JavaScript (raw, jQuery, AJAX), Ruby, Rails, Git, HTML and CSS. I strengthened team skills like communication, empathy, and effective feedback in order foster optimal teamwork environments both in and beyond the program.

#### Operational Support Agent · YMCA OF METROPOLITAN CHICAGO

Mar 2014 to Nov 2015 · Chicago

At the YMCA, I collaborated effectively with various YMCA teams and locations to increase the quality of services and standardize processes and policies, managing customer relations across 23 membership centers. I also performed research and compiled performance metrics for the Director of Operations. In addition, I continuously revised member engagement scripts to improve customer experience, retention, and satisfaction.

### Operational Support Specialist · SPRING REWARDS

Nov 2014 to Feb 2015 · Chicago

Spring Rewards presented me with the opportunity to work across multiple departments to identify and solve IT issues in an entrepreneurial, start-up environment. I also parsed backend server data to compile actionable software error and transaction reports for Director of Operations. In the process, I became proficient in Mobile Device Management and in performing analysis and troubleshooting of live client devices in the field.

#### > VOLUNTEERING

#### Associate Board Member · THE ARTS OF LIFE

Jul 2015 to Feb 2016

The Associate Board is made up of a network of young Chicago area professionals who lead fundraising events and actively volunteer for The Arts of Life, a nonprofit that helps disabled adults create and promote their artwork.

# Finance Lead · LAKES OF FIRE CAMP NATURAL WONDER

Mar 2014 to Jul 2016

Headed team and raised \$15,000 for event expenses, infrastructure and kitchen on yearly basis and co-wrote and submitted art grant that won \$750, as well as had \$600 of materials donated towards art project (all for the sake of fun).

## **>** EDUCATION

#### Middle Tennessee State University

Bachelor of Science Economics 2009

- 3.784 Cumulative GPA. Graduated magna cum laude, top 5% of class.
- Minor: Global Studies. Six years of education in Chile.